# **ALAA ABDELBAKI**

Mobile developer

**\** +216 41 675 757

alaa.abdelbaki@outlook.com

Ariana, Tunisia

github.com/AlaaAbdelbaki

in /in/AlaaAbdelbaki

#### **SUMMARY**

I'm a mobile software engineer, with 2 years of experience in developing cross platform applications with the Flutter framework.

While developing mobile applications, I had the chance to also work on their backend, and ensure submitting them on the Google Play Store and the Apple App Store. **SKILLS** 

Languages: Dart, Java, Kotlin, Swift, Javascript, C#.

Technologies: Flutter, Git, Android, iOS, Jenkins, NestJS,

ExrpessJS, NextJS.

#### EXPERIENCE -

07/2023 - Present

## Flutter developer

**EButler** 

- · Added new features to an existing Flutter application.
- · Worked on improving the real-time chatting feature using GetStream's Stream Chat library.
- · Maintained legacy code.
- · Upgraded the project to newer SDK versions, while performing the required code changes.
- · Pushed updates through Google Play.
- · Developed a redesigned version for mobile and web platforms while referencing a Figma design.
- Implemented new features and perform updates on a NestJS backend.
  Flutter / NestJs / Firebase / Firebase Cloud Messaging / GetStream / Google
  Play / App Store / WhatsApp Business API /

01/2022 - 06/2023

## **Software Engineer**

**Swiss Premium Negoce** 

- · Defined the project's use cases and requirements.
- · Decided which technologies to use based on the technical requirements.
- · Created the database design.
- · Developed the mobile application's UI based on an Adobe XD design.
- · Added new features and updating existing ones.
- · Developed backend features.
- · Write backend documentatio
- Implemented Google Cloud APIs in the mobile application (Google Maps / Google Directions)
- · Integrated Stripe as a payment Gateway.
- Submitted and releacing the application on the Google Play Store and the Apple App Store.
  Flutter / Firebase / Firebase Cloud Messaging / Google Maps API / Google Directions API / ExpressJS / Stripe /

#### EDUCATION

09/2018 - 06/2022

## Engineering degree in computer science

Private Higher School of Engineering and Technology (ESPRIT)

Followed the computer science program, and specialized in mobile applications development Worked on multiple projects in different fields during the cursus, including:

- · Mobile development.
- · Web development.
- · Artificial intelligence.
- · computer vision.
- DevOps.

## PROJECTS -

Flutter / ExpressJS

## Elisys

A warehouse management mobile application, that helps technicians manage their products by simply scanning a QR code.

Flutter

#### **Doroos**

An online learning application, where users can choose from a wide variety of subjects and teachers, and chat with them in real time.

# LANGUAGES

- · English Fluent
- · French B2
- · Arabic Native